[Peter] This was a pretty tough problem.
这是非常棘手的问题
It wasn't only a single gold star problem. It was a 2 gold star problem.
它不是一颗金星难度的问题 而是两颗金星难度
It involves combining a lot of things that you already knew,
它结合了很多你已经学过的知识
including something new, completely new.
也包含一些新的 完全新的东西
But that's part of being a programmer is combining things that you know
这是身为程序员的一部分
and don't know together to solve new problems.
将知道与不知道的事物相结合 来解决新问题
This is a difficult problem.
这是一个困难的问题
You may not know how to do every step, but we can start
你可能不知道每一步该怎么做
by working backwards from our output.
但是我们可以从输出倒回去做
Sometimes it's easier to solve hard problems this way
有时候 以这种方式解决困难的问题比较简单
by breaking them down and even starting from the result.
将问题拆解开来 甚至从结果开始
We know what our result should be.
我们知道结果应该是什么
As described before, 3.14 and so on
如前所述 3.14 ...
should result in printing 3.
要输出 3
And 27.63 should result in printing 28.
27.63 的结果应该是输出 28
To get this, we printed everything before the decimal point.
为了得到这个结果 我们输出小数点前的部分
We did this by printing everything out from a string--
我们从一个字符串中输出
let's say we found it and called it s--
我们找到小数点的位置
before the location of the decimal point.
将它之前的部分 称为 s
Let's say that location is specified by an integer, point.
假设这个位置由整数 point 来表示
So here s needed to be
所以 s 是
3. something.
'3.~' 之类的东西
We don't really know what it is right now.
目前我们不知道它具体是什么
In the second example with 27 as the initial starting point,
在第二个示例中 27 是初始的 point
s = 28 and so on.
s 是 '28.~'
And remember, these had to be strings.
请记住 这些必须是字符串类型
That was what s should have been.
这是 s 本来的类型
Now we need point.
现在我们需要 point
Point represents the location of the decimal point in each string.
point 代表每个字符串里小数点的位置
We can see that from looking at our string.
我们可以在字符串中看到
Given s, we know how to find point.
有了 s  我们知道如何找到 point
It's using the find command.
使用 find 指令
In order to get s, we probably had it as some form of number,
为了得到 s 我们可能有某种形式的数字
and we turned it into a string using str.
我们使用 str 把它转换成字符串
Now the question is, what did num equal?
现在的问题是 num 等于什么？
To figure out what we want num to be, all we have to do is look at s,
为了了解我们想要的 num 是什么 我们必须看 s
since s is just the string form of num.
因为 s 是 num 的字符串形式
Here s is the string 3 with some change.
这里 s 是字符串 '3.' 与其他数字
Num is going to be the same thing, but as a number instead of a string.
num 也是同样的东西 但它是一个数字而不是字符串
And in our second example, we have the same situation,
在第二个例子中 我们有同样的情況
except num is going to be 28 with some decimal remainder.
除了 num 将是 28 和一些小数
The question is, how did we turn our initial value x into num?
问题是 我们如何把我们的初始值 x 转成 num 呢？
We want this method to work for any number x,
我们希望这种方法对任何数 x 都有效
not just the two we have listed here.
不只是这里列出的两组数字
So if the tenth place is .5 or greater,
因此 如果十分位等于或大于 0.5
we want to increase the entire number x to the next nearest whole number.
我们要增加数字 x 到下一个最接近的整数
One way to do this is by simply adding .5, and we're done.
一个方法是简单地加上 0.5 大功告成